MUNNY KUMAR

Gurugram, India storyofcoder1@gmail.com +91 9355242300

Profile

3+ years of experience as a Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the Cryptocurrency industry. I am a passionate technician and enjoy keeping my skills up to date both in and outside of my working environment. I enjoy delivering high-quality software solutions rapidly.

Experience

Nov 2021 - Current

Software Development Engineer 2

WazirX (Binance) - India's Most Trusted Bitcoin & Cryptocurrency Exchange - India

- Migrated NFT Platform from React to Next.
- Revamped the UI of the NFT Platform according to the new design and requirements.
- Built Admin platform Services include administration and operation of NFT platform.
- Fixed breakpoints and rendering issues through integrated Sentry to detect bugs and application breakpoints.

AUG 2019 - Oct 2021

Software Development Engineer

LCX - Liechtenstein Cryptoassets Exchange & Blockchain, Gurugram - India

- Built Cryptocurrency Exchange: A platform for trading on various cryptocurrencies, with real-time history of all cryptocurrencies.
- Built Defi Terminal: A new trading experience with a simple Basic Swap and a Pro Swap functionality, beautiful DEX charting, and our famous limit order functionality.
- Built RVW STO: One-stop Tokenization platform to automate the funding and investor management on the blockchain. Raised \$7.7 Million Fund.
- Built Bots: Automated computer programs that are easy to use, powerful, and
 extremely safe platforms that let you configure, customize and run automated crypto
 exchange bots that execute orders without the need for human intervention.
- Upgraded Terminal: A multi-crypto exchange platform, real-time and full history data on all cryptocurrency markets with trading execution capabilities.
- Upgraded Accounts: A dashboard and platform that handles client's authorization like registration, login, KYC verification, etc.

Enhanced the speed of RESTful APIs and sockets by **45**% using appropriate data structures and algorithms. Increased the Usage of LCX from **5K to 100K+ users** through introducing new products, features, improved the GUI and code structure.

Jan 2019 - Jul 2019

Software Engineer

Acezd, New Delhi - India

- Collaborated with design and development teams to build the front end of a Customer Service Representative platform for an eCommerce business to handle all customer queries.
- Contributed to enhance the working culture of the company by conducting data structures and algorithms workshops.

Education

AUG 2016 - Jul 2019

Bachelor of Technology @ Information Technology

Tech Skills

Frontend Dev	Backend Dev	Database	Other
React JS	Node.js	MongoDB	Data Structure and
Nextjs	JavaScript	Redis	Algorithms
Redux			RESTful Application

Responsibilities

- Developed, upgraded, and managed the multiple products from Frontend and Backend by estimated, performed feasibility analysis and forecast risks, and planned the delivery for new features.
- Synchronizing application of a broad spectrum of defect prevention and detection strategies in order to reduce software development risks, time, and costs.

Extracurricular

- Got 1st position in "Hackon" Web Development competition organized by YMCA UST, Faridabad in 2018.
- An active member of Srijan Club, The fine and art club of YMCA UST Faridabad since Aug 2016.

Links

Github: https://github.com/storyofcoder

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/storyofcoder

HackerEarth: https://www.hackerearth.com/@storyofcoder